Fernando de Oliveira Lima

Software/Hardware Developer | Electrical Engineer

Contact

Luis Inglesias, 120, apt

108

Rio de Janeiro, RJ 22795-060

(21) 98821-4779 folivelima@gmail.com

in://fernando.oliveira

github/fol21

Languages

Fluent English Fluent Portuguese

Basic Spanish

Code

Node.js, Javascript

Typescript

C/C++

Python

Angular, Ionic, React

C# /.NET, .NET Core

Java, Spring

HTML5, CSS3, SCSS

Tools

Linux & Microsoft

Azure, Google Cloud, **IBM Cloud**

Git, Gitlab, Github,

SourceTree

Desenvolvimento de Android apps

KiCAD, Eagle

Espressif, Arduino, Sistemas Embarcados

Photoshop, Lightroom

Profile

Experienced in Software and Hardware development, with activities in the areas of Internet of Things, Web dev, Software, Image Processing among others, besides having interest in Machine Learning and Blockchain, Image and Data Processing, Web.

Has personal projects involving Internet tools of Things, embedded and Web Applications, implemented using tools like Node.js and interfaces in Angular, React.

Education

03/2012-10/2018 Bachelor of Science in Electrical Engineering

Universidade do Estado do Rio de Janeiro (UERJ), Rio de Janeiro, Brazil

Graduated in Rio de Janeiro ,Brazil.

CR = 7.8/10

08/2015–05/2016 Exchange Program in Bachelor of Electrical Engineering, Marietta, USA

Kennesaw State University - Marietta Campus

Exchange undergraduate student through the period of two semesters in Ken-

nesaw State University.

GPA = 3.9/4.0

Experience

10/2018-Radix Engenharia e Software

Trainee

Works in Software projects and web systems. Using Node is, Angular, C++,

Rio de Janeiro, Brasil

Rio de Janeiro, Brasil

San Diego, EUA

Rio de Janeiro, Brazil

C , Java, Python, among others.

11/2016-10/2018 Radix Engenharia e Software

Intern

Worked in innovation projects and web systems, IoT and Cognitive Comput-

ing. Using Node.js, Angular, C++, C, Java, Python, among others.

06/2016-08/2016 University of California, San Diego

Research Exchange Program

Worked as visiting scholar at UCSD, in a Image Processing and mobile de-

velopment project for monitoring the status of surgical incisions.

08/2013–08/2015 National Institute of Space Research (INPE)

Undergraduate Researcher

Was part of a scientific initiation program as an undergraduate researcher. Worked at PROSAICO (Processing of Signals, Applied Intelligence and Com-

munications Laboratory) at UERJ, with cooperation of the National Institute of Space Research (INPE) in a specific research of spectral filtering of high

frequency noises in the Eta atmospheric model data.

Laboratory Technician

Worked as a technician in PROSAICO (Processing of Signals, Applied Intelligence and Communications Laboratory), in maintenance of equipments and computers and developing improvements.

Courses and other activities

01/2014 – Present Founder of UERJBotz Robotics team Universidade do Estado do Rio de Janeiro Is one of the founding members of UERJbotz, a robotics competition team that make it's debut in 2014.

03/2012 - Present IEEEXtreme competitor

IEEE

Competes once a year in the programming marathon iEEEXtreme, since 2012.

08/2012 – 12/2012 Course - Control of Mobile Robots Coursera, Georgia Institute of Technology Completed the online course about control theory applied to mobile robots.

01/2017 Certificados na Udemy

Udemy

- · Advanced C++
- C
- C++ Concurrency
- · Node.is
- Angular
- · Ionic
- · React. React-Native
- Full Stack Development, TDD
- Blockchain

07/2017 – Chair of IEEE UERJ Student Branch

Universidade do Estado do Rio de Janeiro

A Student Branch is an IEEE related initiative of Students for projects in the area of Engineering (mainly Electrical and Computing) for professional development and Projects of Innovation and learning.

22/2018 –26/2018 Chief Coordinator of VI Electrical Engineering Week Universidade do Estado do

Rio de Janeiro

A Week of presentations and courses in the areas of Power, Electronics and Software. Happened between 22/10 - 26/10/2018.

01/2018 Hackton Stefanini, competidor

WINNER OF Hackton da Stefanini . Developer.

03/2018 Hackton Rio2C, competidor

Finalist of Hackton Rio2C, Developer.

04/2018 Hackton Globo, competidor

Competitor of Hackton Globo . Developer.